

ROBERTO MORA

INFORMATION SYSTEMS ENGINEER

BIOGRAPHY

I am a 22 years old Information Systems Engineer from Heredia, Costa Rica. I think knowledge is one of the most important resources, therefore, I consider research and innovation one of the most important tools of a modern professional. I like to read science fiction, discover new places and cooking. I also like to read and write technical articles. Research and Deep Learning Enthusiast

(7) /r

/romogo17

in

/in/romogo17



/@romogo17



/romogo17

EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

National University Costa Rica | October 2017 - November 2018

Project: Databases for the storage and analysis of digital mammograms.

Image segmentation algorithms in C++ and Python

Database extensions for PostgreSQL (using C and Python)

Cross-platform GUI applications (with Javascript)

Machine Leargning Algorithms

DATABASE TEACHING ASSISTANT

National University Costa Rica | February 2018 - November 2018

Class: Database Design and Implementation.

SQL, C++, Query optimization, and database design

LEAD STUDENT DEVELOPER

Santo Domingo Municipality | February 2017 - June 2018

Development of the Municipal Vehicles Control System

(COVEM) for the Santo Domingo Municipality.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN INFORMATIONSYSTEMS ENGINEERING

National University Costa Rica | 2015 - 2018

MACHINE LEARNING A-Z: HANDS-ON PYTHON & R IN DATA SCIENCE

Udemy | December 2017

DIPLOMA IN INFORMATICS
APPLICATIONS PROGRAMMING
National University Costa Rica | 2015 - 2017

• HONORS GRADUATE

Santa María de Guadalupe High School | 2010 - 2014

LANGUAGES





ACKNOWLEDGMENTS & CERTIFICATES

• 2019

HPC School Costa Rica| CeNAT - CNCA

2018

Scrum Fundamentals Certified | ScrumSTUDY

2017

Participation Certificate - Introduction to IoT | IEEE Communications Society

2015

Best Entrance Average Grade to the Exact and Natural Sciences Faculty | National University Costa Rica

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES / MARKUP / SCRIPTING / LIBRARIES

- Javascript, Python, C++, Java, C#
- HTML, CSS
- React, React Native, GraphQL

DATABASES

 Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB

OTHERS

- Git & Github
- Scrum, Docker
- LaTeX, Markdown

SOFT SKILLS

LEADERSHIP AND TEAMWORK

Through the years, I've had the opportunity to successfully lead several work teams, this is why leadership is a skill I've developed with time. Moreover, I strongly believe that teamwork is one of the most important tools for a professional, because it allows a team to be more than the sum of its parts.

CREATIVITY AND INNOVATION

I consider creativity of great value in an industry that grows and reinvents itself at a fast pace. This is why creativity is so important, as it allows to solve problems in a more efficient, innovative manner.

RESPONSIBILITY AND HONESTY

I am an extremely responsible person with a great concern for delivering added value to my work. Moreover, I consider myself a very critic and honest person.

INTERESTS

MACHINE LEARNING

Deep Learning Convolutional Neural Networks Artificial Intelligence Business Intelligence Computer Vision

BIOINFORMATICS

RESEARCH

I am fond of academic research, specially in the fields of Deep Learning, High Perfor-mance Computing and Bioinformatics

